<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<schemalist>
<schema path="/edu/hm/cs/hintview/" id="edu.hm.cs.hintview">

<key name='autoreload' type='b'>
  <default>false</default>
  <summary>Automatically reload a changed document.</summary>
  <description>
  If enabled, hintview will check each time it receives the input focus
  whether the document version on disk is newer than the version currently
  loaded. If so, it will reload the document from disk trying to position
  it as close as possible to the current position. If there are large changes
  to the document, this might not always be the perfect spot.
  </description>
</key>
<key name='dark' type='b'>
  <default>false</default>
  <summary>Render the document in dark mode.</summary>
  <description>
  The document can be rendered in dark mode or in light mode.
  </description>
</key>
<key name='home' type='b'>
  <default>true</default>
  <summary>After opening a new document show the documents home page.</summary>
  <description>
    The author of a document can designate a page of the document as its
    home page. Usualy this is a good page to start reading a document.
    Often this is the first page. In reference documents this is usually
    the table of content.
  </description>
</key>
<key name='gcorrection' type='d'>
  <default>1.8</default>
  <summary>Set the gamma correction for your display.</summary>
  <description>
    Readability of text can often benefit from adjustung the gamma
    correction for the specific display and the ambient light.
    Higher values of gamma make the rendering of text darker,
    lower values make it lighter. Typical values are between 1.8 and 2.2
    but individual circumstances might require different value.
  </description>
</key>
<key name='scale' type='d'>
  <default>1.0</default>
  <summary>Set the scale factor for rendering the document.</summary>
  <description>
    Hintview tries to display a document at its true size if the scale
    factor is set to one. A 10pt font should then have exactly the same
    size on the display as it has in a printed book. Likewise, a line
    that is specified in the document to be 2 inches long, should be
    exactly 2 inches long on the display.
    In many situations, however, it is convenient to use a different
    scale factors. On a small hand-held device, a smaller scale factor
    gives smaller text so that more text will fit on the display.
    Because a hand-held device is typically closer to the eye than
    for example a big TV screen, the smaller text will still be readable.
    On the other hand, for visually impaired users, a larger scale factor
    might make the text easier to read.
  </description>
</key>
<key name='document' type='s'>
  <default>""</default>
  <summary>The file name of the most recent document.</summary>
  <description>
    When started, hintview will usually open the most recent document.
  </description>
</key>
<key name='position' type='t'>
  <default>0</default>
  <summary>The position in the most recent document.</summary>
  <description>
    The position value is a value that hintview uses to remember
    the start of the page most recently viewed in the most recent document.
    Except that the value 0 stands for the start of the document,
    There is simple way to interpret the values of this variable.
  </description>
</key>
<key name='rpx' type='b'>
  <default>true</default>
  <summary>Round glyph position to pixel.</summary>
  <description>
    If enabled, hintview will round the position of glyphs to the next pixel
    boundary. Especially on low DPI screens, with large pixels, this can
    improve readability because otherwise the color of one pixel in the glyph
    will be distributed across several pixel on the screen.
  </description>
</key>
<key name='rpxthreshold' type='d'>
  <default>120</default>
  <summary>The DPI threshold below which glyph positions are rounded.</summary>
  <description>
    Rounding glyph positions to the next pixel boundary will be used only
    if the current DPI settings (including scaling) are below this threshold.
    ON displays with larger DPI values, pixel are considered so small that
    rounding is not deemed necessary. Set the threshold to a large value
    to enforce rounding even on high DPI screens. Setting it to zero is
    another way to disable rounding of glyph positions.
  </description>
</key>
</schema>
</schemalist>
